Fit影视论坛荣誉出品　http://www.fitbbs.com
按照Art.of.the.Devil.2.2005.DVDRip.XviD-DIMENSION版本制作
翻译&制作&校对｜什么也不说
本字幕仅供学习和交流使用，不得用于任何商业目的
使用本字幕所造成的一切后果皆与 Fit 影视论坛无关
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
苏丽夫人的房间在哪？
Where the hell is Mrs. Sulee's house!
这边！
This way!
夫人！夫人！
Mrs! Mrs!
夫人！快开门！苏丽夫人！
Mrs! Hurry up! Mrs. Sulee!
求求你开门吧！我们需要你的帮助！
Open up please! We need your help!
坚强点，我会救你的！
Be strong, Sulee will help you!
他中了高棉诅咒
lt's a Cambodian curse.
恶魔的艺术 2
ART OF THE DEVIL II
当人有压力的时候，大脑的负担会加重
When people are under stress, the human brain will work harder.
随之而来的就是焦虑症
What happens afterwards is called an anxiety disorder.
可以很容易观察到一系列征兆…
The symptoms will be clearly noticed...
…例如头痛逐渐加重，以及情绪易于激动
...when the person has mild to severe headaches, and is agitated easily.
患焦虑症的人手掌容易出汗以及心烦意乱
People with anxiety disorders will also have sweaty palms, and be easily distracted.
如果那些情况得不到治疗的话，选择自杀就没什么奇怪的了
For those that are not treated, suicides are common.
好吧，今天就上到这里，别忘了做作业
Okay, that's all for today, and don't forget to do your assignment.
嘿！如果你们想聊天的话，可以出去聊
Hey! lf you guys want to make out, do it outside the classroom.
有些人是要学习的
Some people in here are trying to learn.
喂，阿塔，是你吗？
Hello, Ta, is that you?
什么？
What is it?
说吧，你知道我抽不出一整天时间
Just spit it out. l don't have all day, you know.
我有很多书要看，而且我很累了，拜拜
l've got a lot of studying to do, and l'm tired. Goodbye.
阿波！你有病啊！
Por! What the heck is your problem!
想给你个惊喜！生日快乐！
Surprise! Happy Birthday!
开玩笑的啦！
lt was a joke!
噢，真的？开玩笑的？
Oh really? A joke huh?
嘿！小金，我们永远都是朋友
Hey! Kim, we've been friends forever.
你知道我对你的感觉
You know how l feel about you.
我想知道，我们是否能超越朋友关系
l want to know if we can be more than just friends.
这比朋友关系要多一点了吧
l think this is a bit more than friends.
喂？
Hello?
喂？是找你的，阿波
Hello? lt's for you, Por.
喂？
Hello?
阿塔！
Ta!
什么？从阿塔的爸爸死之后吗？
What? Since when did Ta's dad die?
是的，这主意不错
Yeah, yeah. it's actually good this way.
我们毕业后我就再没见过阿塔了
l haven't seen Ta since we graduated.
嗨！这是什么时候决定的，阿波？
Hey there! When did this happen, Por?
太好了…
Great...
我们就能像以前一样共同出游了
This way we can hang out together just like the old days!
什么？你说小努吗？她还和以前一样，一点都没变
What? Noot? Oh she's the same, never changes.
[歌词]亲爱的男孩，让我们走近，我们的真爱，没人能了解
Lover boy, let's be real close. As for true Iove, nobody knows.
[歌词]我爱我妻子至深
My wife I love so much.
我为什么要去？
Why am l going?
我已经跟你说过了！我正和我朋友去旅行！
l already told you! l'm going on a trip with my friends!
听着，如果你想让我回去的话，就来接我！
Listen, if you want me to go back, pick me up!
要不然就不要打电话来烦我！再见！
Otherwise, don't even bother calling! Goodbye!
你给谁打电话？
Who were you talking to?
没有谁
No one.
快点，我们走吧，火车来了
Come on, let's go. Our train is here.
闭嘴，阿柯，上车之后别再烦我了！
Shut up, Ko. Don't even bother getting aboard!
走开！
Go away!
高中毕业两年了…
Two years after our high school's graduation...
…我们看上去都变了，从一群遵守纪律的乡村学校的孩子
...we all seem changed somehow, from a regular group of rural school kids...
…变成像现在这样成熟起来
...to the grown ups we are now.
但对我而言，我们旧时走过的老路的影像…
But for me, it's as if the memories of our old path...
…又逐渐在眼前清晰起来
...slowly are emerging into clear sight.
如果说生命中有很多路要走的话…
lf life is filled with many paths to take...
…那么最重要的就是…
...then what's most important...
…我们应该选择好在分叉点的时候往哪走…
...are all the junctions where we choose...
…以及考虑好它对我们未来的影响
...and how it shapes our futures.
对我而言，这甚至使我意识到，未来是由我们的愿望所生
For me, this event made me realize that the future comes from our wishes.
我们的过去，其实就决定了我们的现在
As for our past, it actually defines us.
[两年前]
2 YEARS AGO
小金！
Kim!
我会尽快看完的
l'll read it as soon as l can.
我得走了
l better get going.
快上来，车开慢点！
Hurry up, slow poke!
终于知道你为什么总迟到了！在这里遇到漂亮MM了，是吧？
So that's why you are always late! Been hitting on the chicks here, huh?
你很聪明啊，走吧，快开车！
You're slick, you know that? Go ahead, drive on!
嘿，小金，他给了你什么啊？能给我看看吗？
Hey Kim, what is it? May l see it?
你无聊啊
Don't be silly.
他是个讨人喜欢的家伙，他还是这个区最好的运动员呢
He's a cute guy, and the district's top athlete too!
拜托，别说啦！
Come on, knock it off!
小金，小心点，小玉在那里
Kim, watch out, Kaew is right there.
这里到处都是学生
There are kids everywhere here.
噢，他们来这里只是帮老师批改学生作业的
Oh, they're just here to help the teacher check the homework.
钱给你
Here is the money.
来支烟？
You want a smoke?
噢，不用了，老师不喜欢抽烟的
Oh, no thanks. The teacher wouldn't like that.
嘿，阿波，把另一张递给我
Hey, Por, pass me another one.
阿柯！不要吊儿郞当了！
Ko! Stop fooling around!
阿柯！小心批注，你别把事情弄糟了
Ko! Careful with the marks, you're going to mess it up!
你搞那些乱七八糟的符号干什么？
Why the weird patterns?
只是一个小弯折的形状，没事的
Nothing wrong with a little zig zag.
什么弯折，去死吧
To heck with the zig zags.
弯折的形状与爱情是有关联的，宝贝
A zig zag line to love, babe.
不要再玩了
Cut it out.
我给大家拿了甜点来
l've got dessert for us.
喔，老师你太好了，老师！
Wow, that's so generous of you, Teacher!
阿柯，小心图纸！
Ko, careful there with the drawings!
评分进展如何？
So how is it with the grading?
我们快做完了
We're almost done now.
我能看看吗？
Can l see?
阿柯偷了很多懒
Ko slacked off a lot.
小金，你的英语很棒！
Kim, you're skilled with your English!
你为什么不吃呢？
Why don't you eat dear?
你大老远地跑来我家…
You came all the way to my house and...
…如果不品尝一下我做的盐渍芒果就回去的话…
...if you go back without trying my famous pickled mangos...
…真是太可惜了
...you're going to miss out on something good.
谢谢
Thank you.
妈，给我一千泰铢
Mom, l need 1 000 baht.
我马上回来，孩子们
l'll be right back, kids.
她真是个好老师
She is really a nice teacher.
他的哥哥阿塔向她要钱的时候，她不会有半点犹豫的
Her brother Ta asked for money and she didn't even hesitate.
那个小农是母亲的孩子
That Nong is a moma's boy.
而阿塔则是父亲的孩子
But Ta here, is a dady's boy.
在这个家庭里，女的权力大
ln this house, the mother has the upper hand.
嘿，谁打我的头？
Hey, who hit my head?
想来赛车吗？快点！
Want to race? Hurry up!
阿波，阿柯说阿塔是父亲的孩子，那是什么意思啊？
Por, when Ko said that Ta is a dady's boy, what did he mean by that?
噢，阿塔是普拉威先生的儿子
Oh, Ta is Prawaet's son.
阿塔的生母死后，普拉威先生与潘老师相爱了
Mr. Prawaet fell in love with Mrs. Panor after Ta's real mom died.
后来我们的潘老师就生下了小农
Anyway, our teacher, Panor gave birth to Nong later.
阿塔更爱他的生母，而不是潘老师
Ta favors his father more than our teacher, Panor.
你看到阿塔学习那样勤奋，他完全是为了他父亲
You see Ta being so studious, but it's all for his dad's sake.
- 抓紧了，小金  - 再见，阿塔！
- Hang on Kim.  - See you later, Ta!
小金，小金…
Kim, Kim...
我们到了
We're here.
嘿，阿塔…
Hey, Ta...
阿塔！
Ta!
阿塔！你还好吗
Ta! How are you!
你想我们吗？
Did you miss us or what?
我想你们所有人
l missed all of you guys.
嘿，阿塔！
Hey Ta!
听到你父亲的消息我很难过
Sorry about your dad and all.
你还好吧？
You doing all right?
我很好，你呢？
l'm fine, and you?
很久没见你了，小金，你还好吗？
Haven't seen you in a while Kim. You okay?
很好
l'm okay.
我们走吧，你爸爸在等着我们呢
Let's go guys. Your dad is waiting for us by now.
阿柯，你这乌鸦嘴！
Ko, you and your filthy mouth!
嘿，伙计，你要好好看看小努了，两年没见到她了
Hey buddy, check out Noot. Haven't seen her for two years.
现在她的身材很火辣，没觉得吗？
Now, she got a great body, don't you think?
我要是能那么丰满就好了
What l wouldn't do to get me some of that.
你也想吧？和我一起努力吧，肯定行的啦
You want some? l'll share. lt's all good.
阿塔，后来怎么样了？
Ta, so what's up with that story?
你打算告诉我们吗？
Are you going to fill us in or what?
喔，你们毕业后…
Well, after you guys graduated...
妈妈就一直有无穷无尽的麻烦
Mom had problem after problem.
我后来回了家
Actually, l just came back home.
等等，你一直住哪的？
Wait up, so where have you been?
住学校里，小农就是麻烦的根源
Disciplinary school. Nong was the one with the problems.
但是我不能及时解决那些问题
But l couldn't help in time.
他是故意溺水而死的，我被当作替罪羊抓了起来
He drowned on purpose. l got caught as the scape goat.
发生那事之后，爸爸开枪自杀了
After that, dad shot himself.
我最近刚被释放出来，所以现在才能替爸爸操办丧事
l just got released actually, so now l can take care of my father's funeral.
事情过去很久了，伙计
lt was a long time ago, buddy.
我觉得你应该忘了它
l think you should just forget about it.
嘿，我们不如到了阿塔家里再聊吧
Hey, why don't we talk about all this at Ta's house.
这里又热又闷的
lt's hot and muggy here.
小努，我们走吧
Noot, let's go.
看那里！
Look over there!
发生了什么事！
There's something going on over there!
住手！你们被捕了！
Stop! You are under arrest!
阿柯，你带着小农
Ko, take Nong with you.
趴在地上！
Get down on the ground!
你认识这些小流氓吗？
You know these hooligans?
不认识
No.
让你一辈子记住
Remember this 'til the day you die.
如果你想在哪里惹事毁了自己的将来，那就完全是你的错
lf you want to screw your life up somewhere, it's your business.
但是你不要把我儿子牵扯进去！你听懂没有？
Just don't bring my son into it! Do you understand me?
你们两个碍手碍脚的东西！你们父子俩都一样！
You retard! The both of you, father and son!
嘿！你侮辱我就算了，不要说我爸，他和这事没有一点关系
Hey! Insult me, not dad. He's got nothing to do with this.
你竟敢对我这样大声说话？
You dare raise your voice with me?
你竟敢对我顶嘴！你这个小混帐！
How dare you even talk back to me! You pathetic bastard!
阿塔！
Ta!
够了！过来
That's enough! Come on.
你冷静一点，停手吧，过来，我们走
And as for you, calm down. Stop it already. Come on, let's go.
好！既然你这样恨我
Fine! You hate me so much.
那么你给我记住：如果你将来变成一个小偷，你就会想起今天所发生的事了
Just remember, when you are a low life thief, you'll remember this day.
阿塔，你知道，你对我来说很重要
Ta, you are something, you know that.
你为什么那样恨她呢？
How come you have to hate her so much?
就算不是为了你，你也要为了我而有一些同情心啊
lf not for yourself, then have some sympathy for me at least.
擦了些药膏之后，可能就会好些了
After some rubbing ointment, you'll probably feel better.
记住，再也不要那样做了
Remember, just don't do it again.
还有件事：我希望你能爱小农
One more thing, l want you to love Nong.
至少他是你唯一的弟弟啊
He is your only brother at the very least.
喔，太酷了！上面的图像天堂啊
Wow, this is cool! lt's like heaven.
我喜欢！
l love it here!
放松点！放松点
Take it easy there. Easy does it.
看好了！老彭的纹身工具真不是盖的
Check it out! Pawn's stuff is really good.
他们说那些工具是从高棉宗教仪式上所得
They say it's from Cambodian rituals.
连小农都来这里做纹身
Nong even came here to do his tattoo.
他那皮肤连刀都刺不穿的
No knife or blade can cut through his skin.
阿塔？你已经见过了吧？
Ta? You've seen it, right?
你比我还先见过呢，阿柯
You first, Ko.
喝掉！喝掉！
Drink up! Drink up!
干杯！
Cheers!
这里有谁不是我的学生的，请出去
Everyone who's not my student, get out.
你们学会喝酒了是吧？是吧？
So now you are learning to drink? Are you not?
教练…
Coach...
闭嘴！谁让你说话了？
Shut up! Who said you could talk?
你的学号是多少？
What is your lD number?
嘿！
Hey!
想吓我是吧？
Want to be a bully?
你们想喝酒是吧？想喝得烂醉是吧？
You want to drink? Want to be a drunk?
把头伸过来！过来！
Come here! Come here!
叫你们喝！
Drinking!
醉酒学生！
Drunken students!
明天叫你们家长来
Tomorrow, bring your parents.
我要让你们记住
l'm going to make you remember this.
你也相信他的话？
You believe him too?
他的话根本不足信！
His words aren't believable!
他每天都在制造麻烦
He causes problems everyday.
他和他的那些疯朋友们才刚惹了麻烦不久…
Him and his crazy friends just got into trouble with the officials...
…你还没忘吧！
...if you remember!
你好好想想吧，你听信了他的一面之词
You think it over. lt's his word over mine!
阿塔，我告诉过你无数次了，不要说你继母的坏话
Ta, l've told you countless times not to bad mouth your stepmother.
但是爸爸！我亲眼看到他们做那事的
But dad! l saw them together.
不要再有下一次！
Make sure this never happens again!
爸爸…
Dad...
我们每天还要在那里屋里打扫卫生…
We still have to do our daily cleaning chores in that room...
…所以我觉得我们不如把摄相机偷来，以便利用
...l say lets steal that camera and put it to good use.
阿塔，听我说，如果能偷拍到的话…
Ta, listen to me man, if you do this both the coach and...
…教练和我们的潘老师两个人都要玩完了
...our teacher, Panor can kiss their futures goodbye.
谁在那里？
Who's there?
快追！你为什么还站着不动？
Hurry up! Why are you still standing here?
嘿！停下！
Hey! Stop it!
回来！
Come back here!
泰尔！
Tair!
你们都清楚，你们才刚结束见习期
You all know that you've just finished up your probation.
现在你们偷了学校的设备，也就意味着会被开除
And now that you have stolen school equipment, it will mean expulsion.
我要把你们交给警察处理
l have to hand you over to the police.
教练，我求你不要报警
Coach, l'm begging you not to call the police on us.
那么我就需要一些回报了
This would mean l need something in return.
答应吗？
May l?
不要，请停下，我求你了
No. Please stop. l'm begging you.
请停下，我求你了
Please, l'm begging you.
我们快离开这里！
Let's get out of here!
快点！
Go on!
给我站住！
Stop it right there!
除偷盗学校财物之外…
Other than theft of school property...
…你们还将背上殴打、袭击教师的罪名
...you'll be charged with battery and assault.
你们都想进监狱是吧？
You all want to go to jail or what?
你们是不是真的想进监狱？你也是吧？
You are really asking for jail time? What about you?
你干什么！
What the hell are you doing!
但是别担心，我可以有条件地把你们都放了
But don't worry, l've got just the thing to set you all free.
你这个混帐！
You bastard.
停下！你最好不要碰她！你连畜牲都不如！
Stop! You better not touch her! You're not human!
你不得好死！
You low life!
马上放开我！听到没有？停下！混帐！
You let me go this instant! You hear me? Stop it! Bastard!
放开我！你这个混帐！
Let me go! You bastard!
停下！
Stop it!
不要！
No!
你这个混帐！
You bastard!
放开我！
Let go of me!
妈的！
Damn!
你们来这里找我之前，都想好了吗？
Before you decided to come here to see me, you've thought it over already?
这就像骑虎背般危险
lt's like riding on the back of a tiger.
你预料不到它什么时候会回咬你一口
You never know when it will turn around and bite.
我只想警告你们
l'm just warning you all.
世上之事，你一旦尝试，它就会跟随着你，直到你死去的那一天
Things of this nature, once tried, it will stick with you 'til the day you die.
明白吗？
Understand?
要想做成功，必须要有合适的方法
The way to do this right, you have to get proper mediums.
生日…
Birth dates...
个人照片…
Personal photo...
个人财物…
Personal property...
还有最后一样：他所踩过的泥土
Lastly, you need the dirt he steps upon.
这些东西你们都能给我弄来吗？
Can you get me all those things?
绝对不要睁开你们的眼睛
Don't even think of opening your eyes.
早上好
Good day there.
Good day to you.
这里的东西很好吃，我是常客
The food here is good. l eat here all the time.
伙计们，你们听说教练的事了吧？他死了！
Hey guys, did you hear about the coach? He's dead!
我跟你说过多少次了，阿柯？
How many time l have to tell you, Ko?
不要再提那事了
No more talk about that incident.
有没有人看到阿塔？
Anyone seen Ta around?
怎么了？
What's going on?
发生什么事了？
What's happening?
嘿，你在干什么？
Hey, where are you going?
我们去看看
Let's go find out.
让开！
Get out of the way!
阿塔，你在听我说话吗？
Hey Ta, are you listening?
嗯，是的，我在听
Uh, yeah. l'm listening.
那么后来怎么样了？
So, what happened after that?
我觉得很奇怪，你继母为什么不去参加你爸爸的火葬？
l wondered, why your stepmom never went to your father's cremation.
她仍怀恨在心吗？
Or is she still angry about it all?
她又回去靠买盐渍芒果为生了
She's back making her living selling pickled mangoes again.
我也不清楚，我有自己的生活，她也一样
l don't know man, l just live my life, and she has her own.
我们很少说话的
We don't talk much.
上来吧，小金，小心点
Come on Kim. Careful there.
每人五十泰铢吗？
That's fifty baht each?
是的
Yes.
给你钱
Here's the money.
感谢搭载
Thanks for the ride.
先生，你找多钱了！
Sir, you gave us the wrong change!
噢，奶奶好
Oh, hello there, grandmother.
我们就待在这边
We'll be staying on this side.
除非不得已，否则不要去那边打扰奶奶
lf it isn't necessary, don't go over there and bother grandma.
噢，你的房子太乱了
Oh boy, your room's a mess.
至少还能住
lt's livable.
你们先把行李暂时放在这里吧
You guys just leave your stuff here for now.
你们先去拜一下神祠，我来帮你们铺床，好吗？
First go pay respects to the shrine, while l make your beds up. All right?
当然可以，我们走
Sure thing. Come on, let's go.
快点，小金
Come on, Kim.
阿波，你觉得潘老师看到我们会不会不高兴？
Por, do you think that teacher Panor will be happy to see us?
呃，我不敢确定
Um, l'm not too sure.
她会不会大哭起来
Oh for crying out loud.
你只需告诉小金这一点就行了：不确定潘老师是不是还会为当年的事抓狂
Just tell Kim that you're not sure if our teacher Panor is still crazy or not!
动作快点！动作快点！
Hurry up! Hurry up!
加快速度！
Quicken up the pace!
努力干活，加快速度
Work hard. Hurry up.
老师，你…
Teacher, are you...
我想说你还好吗？
l mean how are things?
你们也还好吗？你们觉得我怎么样？
And what about you kids? How do you think l am?
你还是那么美
You're still beautiful.
我老了
l'm old now.
呃，老师，你怎么了？
Um, what's the matter, teacher?
是我舅舅的电话
Oh my uncle's calling me.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
喂
Hello.
听说你们都搬到大城市曼谷去了
l hear that my students all moved out of here to the big city of Bangkok.
在那里还好吗？继续进修吗？
How is it there? Further study?
阿波现在学法律…
Por is a law student...
…而阿柯是工程专业的
...while Ko over here is an engineering student.
小努正在学英语，他准备和泰尔一起去澳大利亚深造
Noot is studying English and preparing to go to Australia with Tair.
你还是那样健谈
You are always the chatty girl.
我还记得你以前是班上第二名呢
And from the number two student of the class, too.
喔，您过奖了
Well, l'm flattered by that.
但是如果我以前是第一名的话，我会太骄傲的
But l'd be proud if l was number one instead of two.
你学的是什么专业？
So what field are you studying in these days?
医学方面的
l'm studying to be a doctor.
真的？是真的吗，先生？
Really? ls it true, Mister?
你不是故意骗我回去的吧？
You're not pulling my chain or anything like that, are you?
好吧，我想办法尽快赶回去
Yes, yes l'll try to find a way to go as quickly as l can.
喂？喂？
Hello? Hello?
你们的手机有信号吗？
Anyone here have a signal?
能借我打个电话回家吗？
Can l borrow your phone to call back home?
不走运啊
No luck.
这里没信号的
There is no signal here.
你只有到那个旧神祠那里才有信号
You can only get a signal by that old shrine over there.
唉，我该怎么办啊？
Oh great, what am l going to do?
小努？有什么急事吗？
Noot? What's the urgency?
现在我爸爸住院了…
Well, right now my dad is in the hospital...
我舅舅在火车站等我
And my uncle is waiting for me at the train station.
我想我不能在这待下去了
So l don't think l can stay.
喔，真的吗？
Woah, really?
那你真的要马上回去？
So you really have to go back right now?
不要生我的气，好嘛？
Don't be angry at me. Please?
我必须回去啊
l really have to go back. All right?
不要生气，不要生气
Don't be angry. Don't be angry.
喔！这是干什么啊！下次记得先叫我们来
Wow! What a view! Next time, call us before things get hot!
阿柯，闭上你的嘴吧！
Hey Ko, shut it already!
伙计们…
Oh man...
小努！你搞定了吧？
Noot! Are you finished yet?
老师叫我们来找你
The teacher told us to come get you.
是啊，她还有些你们女孩间的事要交代你，我们走吧！
Yeah, just finish up doing what you girls do, and let's go!
你真恶心！
Screw you!
嘿，小努的舌头感觉如何？
Hey, thinking of Noot's tongue?
现在我把我的舌头借你用
l'll let you borrow mine for now.
你真是自讨苦吃！
You're really asking for it!
你们谁看到阿塔了吗？
Any of you guys seen Ta around?
我到处都找不到他
l can't find him anywhere.
我刚才看到他在那边的花园里
l saw him in the garden over there.
阿波，我觉得你和小金成双成对的，让阿塔不愉快了
Por, l think Ta is uncomfortable with you and Kim being couples and all.
你应该和阿塔澄清一下
You should clear it up with Ta.
阿塔，你想过你的未来吗？
Ta, have you thought of your future at all?
我一直都在想，并且付诸巨大的努力
l think of it all the time and l put great effort into it.
我向成为一个医生的目标而努力学习…
l made the cut for my studies as a doctor and...
…父母都为此很高兴
...mom and pop are really happy about it.
我真的想为之尽全力
l really want to give it my best shot.
我们应该分手了
We should split up.
小金！我不明白！
Kim! l don't understand!
我为你以及你所取得的成绩而高兴
l am proud of you and your grades.
但我不明白，为什么我们不能再见面
But l don't see why we can't still see each other.
你不会明白的
You don't understand.
你说得对，我不明白
You're right. l don't understand.
我不明白我们为什么要分手
l don't get why we have to break up.
你想知道我的一切，我都告诉你了
You wanted to know everything about me and l've told you.
我还能做什么？
What else do l have to do?
阿塔，放开我！你弄疼我了！
Ta, let me go! You're hurting me!
曾经发生的一切…我甚至未曾开始过！你明白吗？
Everything that happened... l didn't start it! You understand?
告诉我真正的原因，为什么要分手？
Tell me the real reason why. Why the breakup?
放开我！
Let go of me!
我只想选择一条对我好的路走，你不是我命中的那个人
l just want to choose what's good for me and, you're not the one for me!
你不是！
You're not the one!
妈的！
Damn!
阿波，如果你再那样的话，我要生气了
Por, if you keep doing that, l'll really be angry.
阿波，你刚才听到什么声音了吗？
Por, did you hear something just now?
什么声音？
What sound?
没什么，也许是风声吧
lt's nothing. Probably the wind.
呃，小金？
Um, Kim?
如果你有时间的话，我想跟你谈一下
lf you're finished, l'd like a word with you.
我有些话要说
l have something to say.
我也是
So do l.
阿塔…
Ta...
有时候我有种负罪感
Sometimes l feel that l am the guilty one.
你看得出来，阿波现在和我是一对
You can probably see that Por and l are a couple now.
这是我的决定，与阿波无关
lt was my decision. lt's not Por's fault.
如果非要说有人错的话，那也是我的错
lf it was anyone was wrong, it would be me.
小金…
Kim...
过去两年中，我一直想办法联系你
For the past two years, l've tried to get in touch with you.
但你根本不关心我
But you never cared for me.
我从未忘记过你，小金
l never forgot you, Kim.
不要再像以前一样了
Please don't do that again.
忘了过去吧
Forget the past.
回到朋友中去吧
Let's go back to all our friends.
他们都去哪了？
Where did they all go?
阿塔！
Ta!
水太冷了！
lt's freezing!
真有你们的！
You guys are something!
我赢了！
l win!
这个娱乐主意不错
Nice idea for fun.
阿塔，你觉得冷吗？
Ta, you cold or something?
我喝了几口水了
l swallowed some of the water.
我看到水下有人！
l saw someone under the water!
你看到的是东西，不是人，这里只有我们
You're seeing things! We're the only ones in the water.
阿塔，你奶奶瘦得皮包骨似的，她是不是也像芒果一样被浸渍过啊？
Hey Ta, your grandma skinny dipping?
去死吧！
Piss off!
两年过去了，一切仍依旧，真有点不可思议啊
lt's amazing that two years have past and everything is still the same.
我觉得有些东西变了
l think l feel something has changed.
很严肃地说，我真的觉得有些东西变了
No seriously, l think something has changed.
我看到了
l saw it.
阿柯，你看到了什么？
Ko, what did you see?
看到了胸部！圆圆的小土墩！
Breasts! Round mounds!
少来了，阿柯！
Cut it out, Ko!
泰尔，你哪天要是不想当同志了，记得要告诉我啊
Tair, call me when you decide not to be gay.
老师，你在蒸什么呢？
Teacher, what's cooking?
闻起来真棒，辛辣鸡肉汤看起来不错啊
Smells good. Spicy chicken broth looks good.
觉得不错的话就全都拿去吃吧
lf it looks good, take the whole pot.
那里还有很多鱼咖喱馅饼
And over there is plenty of fish curry pie.
我们开餐去吧！
Let's setup for dinner!
嘿，小猫咪，小猫咪
Hey, kitty, kitty.
你想和我们一起吃吗，嗯？
Want to eat with us, huh?
你不和我们一起吃吗？
You're not going to eat with us?
你们自便吧，我留有自己吃的东西
Help yourself, l already had my share.
我要深思祈祷一会儿
l'm going to meditate and pray for a while.
老师，有什么不对吗？
ls there anything wrong, teacher?
你知不知道，每当我多看你们一眼，我就愈想回到学校去教书
You know, the more l see you kids, the more l want to go back and teach.
到我这来，小猫咪，你在哪里？
Here kitty kitty. Where are you?
过来吃饭喽
Come and get your dinner.
到我这来，小猫咪
Here kitty kitty.
我把吃的留在这里了
l'm going to leave it right here.
小金！
Kim!
奶奶！
Grandma!
奶奶！你不能吃它的，奶奶！
Grandma! You can't eat that, grandma!
别吃了，奶奶！
Stop eating it, grandma!
你们这些孩子根本不关心我！我很饿！我饿！
You kids don't care for me! l'm hungry! Hungry!
你们来帮下我好吗？
You guys, help me out will you?
她年纪太大了，甚至都不知道自己吃的是什么
She is senile. She doesn't know what she's eating!
奶奶，不要吃了，你需要休息，我带你去
Grandma, no. You need to get some sleep. l'll take you.
我快要饿死了，我不能睡觉
But l'm starving. l can't go to sleep.
我好饿！
l'm hungry!
阿塔，你奶奶怎么样了？
Hey Ta, how is your grandmother?
别担心，她只是年纪太大了
Don't worry, she's just senile.
别为这事烦心了
Don't fret over it.
嘿，不要急
Hey, take it easy there.
泰尔，你是不是吓坏了？
Tair, are you scared?
我吓坏了？我什么也不怕
Me, scared? l'm scared of nothing.
但是我怕
But l'm scared.
我觉得这地方从今天傍晚后就怪怪的
l think there's something weird about this place. Ever since this evening.
今天屋里来了很多客人
Today, we have many guests in the house.
妈妈要打扮得漂漂亮亮的
Mother will have to dress up nice and pretty.
你也要和我一样，我的儿子
You should too, my son.
你也要清洁一下了
You will probably need to clean up a bit as well.
[印度三大主神之一的毁灭神]
可能你与湿婆同在，但我还是有点不放心
You may be with the three eyed god, but l'm still worried for you.
你得明白我的用心，我这样做是为你好
You have to understand. l'm doing this for your own good.
去和湿婆待在一起吧，你就会变得圣洁
Go stay with the three eyed god. So you will be clean.
妈妈现在要帮你清洁一下
Mother will have to clean you up now.
你就会变干净了，亲爱的
So that you will be clean, my dear.
我们已经拜过了该地的众神灵
We've already paid our respects to the gods of these grounds.
我想现在不会再出其他问题了吧
l don't think there will be any more problems from now on.
我们去吃点东西吧
Let's go eat.
嗯，真好吃！
Um, this is delicious!
阿柯，不要像猪一样，用勺子吃好不好
Hey Ko, stop being a pig. Use a spoon.
说什么呢？我太饿了
What? l'm starving.
是木地板的声音
lt's just the sound of the wooden floor.
阿柯！你真恶心！
Ko! That's disgusting!
你就不能不打饱嗝吗？还有一个呢
You can't handle a burp? Here, have another one.
你们这些怪异的贱小孩，你们不圣洁！
You freaking bastard child. You're unclean!
泰尔？你刚才说什么？
Tair? What did you just say?
什么？我什么也没说啊
What? l didn't say anything.
鸡汤很好喝！
This chicken soup is delicious!
谢谢
Thank you.
阿柯，不要把食物搅得一团乱
Hey Ko. Stop hogging up the food.
嘿，尝尝这个吧
Hey, try some of this.
是小努！汤里的肉是小努的肉！
Noot! The meat in the soup is Noot's!
阿塔！你继母现在还没完全恢复正常吧？
Ta! Your stepmom isn't completely sane yet, is she?
阿塔，她去哪了？
Ta, where is she?
我下楼找找，她可能在楼下
l'm going to see downstairs. She might be downstairs.
小金？
Kim?
小金！
Hey Kim!
Kim!
把小金叫醒！
Wake up Kim!
她怎么了？
What's wrong with her?
小金！
Kim!
你们来看这个
You guys check this out.
潘老师为什么要这样干？
Why is Teacher Panor doing this?
你们还记得彭先生那天跟我们说过的话吗？
You guys remember what Mr. Pawn told us that day?
你们要吃掉你们所超度的人的肉
You must eat the flesh of those you release.
以从他们身上获得力量
ln order to gain the powers from them.
那么她为什么要那样干呢？
And why did she do that?
是因为她还没忘记那段往事吗？
Or is it because she hasn't forgotten about the past.
你们应该把她的录像拍下来给你爸爸作为证据
l think you should get her on video for your dad as proof.
没错，我觉得那是个好主意！
Yeah, l think that's a great idea!
那样爸爸就会相信我一次了
That way, dad will finally believe me for once.
我们还可以把录像放给全校人看
Plus, while we're at it, might as well show the whole school.
你们说呢？
What do you think?
太好了！那就是你们想看到的…
Good! The visions you want...
我会让你们看看，你们的满足所带来的后果
l'll let you see to your satisfaction.
阿塔？你说话啊
Ta? Say something.
你对你妈妈一无所知吗？
Your mom doesn't know anything?
我已经跟你们说过了，在过去两年中…
l already told you that for the past 2 years...
我没跟她住在这里
l wasn't here with her.
泰尔？你怎么了？
Tair? What's wrong?
泰尔？怎么了？
Tair? What's the matter?
冷静点，泰尔！
Calm down, Tair!
泰尔！
Tair!
阿波！我们离开这里吧！求你了！
Por! Let's all get out of here! Please!
快！我们走！
Come on! Let's go!
有只船！帮帮我们！
A boat! Help us!
救命！！帮帮我们！在这里！
Help!! Help us! Over here!
该死！
Damn!
在那里！
Over there!
帮帮我们！救救我们！这里！救救我们！
Help us! Save us! Over here! Save us!
不要妨碍我的事！
Don't interfere!
小金！
Kim!
阿塔！
Ta!
小金！
Kim!
你想离开我是吧？嗯？
You want to leave me? Huh?
我觉得你办不到
l think you won't be able to do that.
如果你走不了路了，你就不能离开我了，对吗？
lf you can't walk away, then you won't leave me. ls that correct?
你说呢？
What do you think?
小金
Kim.
小金，你没事吧？
Kim, are you all right?
快上来！
Hurry up!
小金？她怎么样了？
Kim? How is she?
阿塔，刚才我看到了一些东西
Ta. Just now l saw something.
小金？
Kim?
那是我爸爸的枪啊
That's my dad's gun.
小金，你怎么知道枪放在哪的？
Kim. How did you know where to find that?
我不知道
l don't know.
但是在幻像中，我看到这把枪，从他爸爸的手里掉到了这地上
But in my visions, l saw it falling out of his father's hand and land here.
里面有人！
There's someone in there!
阿塔！那是你爸爸！阿塔！
Ta! That's your dad! Ta!
这里究竟发生过什么事？
What the hell is going on here?
怎么会这样？
How can this be?
你爸爸火葬的时候我们都去了的，不是吗？
We went to your father's cremation, didn't we?
可能我像你们一样，都被骗了
I was probably fooled the same way you guys got fooled.
泰尔，你到底看到了什么？
Tair. What exactly are you seeing?
快点，大家抓住她！泰尔！别怕！
Quickly, everyone hold her down! Tair! Calm down.
我们带她去祭祀间里！
Let's take her to the sacred room!
伙计们，快点！
Hey guys, hurry up!
泰尔！你怎么了！
Tair! What's wrong?
别怕，别紧张！
Calm down. Get a grip of yourself!
我不去！
l'm not going!
我们走！
Let's go!
放开我！
Let me go!
泰尔!！泰尔!！泰尔！
Tair! Tair! Tair!
小金！
Kim!
救我！阿波，快救我！
Help me! Por, help me please!
小金！
Kim!
快救我啊！
Help me please!
小金！
Kim!
救我出去！快开门！
Get me out of here! Open up the doors!
小金！
Kim!
我忘了告诉你，还有个门可以进祭祀间的
l forgot to tell you there is another way into the sacred room.
小金！
Kim!
没事了，小金，你现在安全了
lt's okay Kim. You're safe now.
我们待在这里应该安全了
lf we stay in here, we should be safe.
我希望你们从实招来！
l want you to confess!
你们这些人之中谁是主谋？
Out of all you people here, who is the mastermind?
我打算给你们这些人上一节课
l'm going to teach you all a lesson.
到底是谁？
Who?
是不是你？
You?
还是你？
Or you?
救救我吧，我不想死
Please help me. l don't want to die.
我承认我错了
l confess l was wrong.
我还不想死，求求你救救我好吗？
l don't want to die yet. Help me, please?
泰尔，冷静一下
Tair calm down.
泰尔？
Tair?
泰尔，冷静一下
Tair calm down.
我不应该卷进这事的
l shouldn't have been involved.
我不应该卷进这事的！
l shouldn't have been involved!
泰尔…
Tair...
你不如再哭大声点！说一次就够了！
For crying out loud! Shut up for once!
哭有什么用！
What good is crying going to do!
我们现在已经够麻烦的了，根本没时间管你哭来哭去的！
We already have enough to deal with, let alone your crying!
你个疯子给我安静点，阿柯！
You freaking shut your mouth, Ko!
闭上你的乌鸦嘴！
You and your filthy mouth!
我想知道，我和你谁会先死！
l want to know, between me and you, who's going to die first!
我刚才跟你说过闭嘴了吧！
Didn't l tell you to shut it?
你是说过，但是我凭什么听你的
That's right, l'm not going to shut up.
我叫你闭上你的臭嘴！
l said shut your hole!
你想怎么样，阿柯？
What are you going to do about it, Ko?
你们不要碰我！
You guys stay away from me too!
如果我以前不认识你们的话，今天我也不会在这里碰上这些鬼事情！
lf l hadn't known all of you, today l wouldn't be here to see shit like this!
我叫你闭嘴，泰尔！
l said, shut up Tair!
我们当时不应该搞什么计划的！不应该去偷拍的！
We wouldn't have planned it out! We wouldn't have to shoot that video!
就不会惹这些麻烦了！
We wouldn't have gotten into trouble!
也不会被那个死教练随意玩弄了！
We wouldn't have been sexually abused by that damn coach!
也不会吃下小努的肉了！
We wouldn't have to eat Noot's flesh!
泰尔！泰尔！泰尔！
Tair! Tair! Tair!
够了！
That's enough!
现在你可以闭嘴了吗？
Now will you shut up?
我们不是都说好，不再提那事了吗？
Didn't we all agree to never mention that incident ever again?
泰尔，你听我说！
Tair, you listen up!
现在每个人都和你一样害怕
Right now, everyone is scared just as you are.
但是你现在需要做的就是冷静，集中你的精神！
But what you have to do now is calm down. Focus!
明白吗？
Do you understand?
我们一起来祈祷吧
Come on, let's all pray.
我们祈祷佛祖会保佑我们
Let's pray that Buddha will protect us.
泰尔，你他妈的笑什么？
Tair, what the hell are you laughing about?
你们他妈的又在祈祷什么！
What the hell are you all praying about!
什么都不会保佑像你们一样的坏人！
Nothing can protect bad people like you!
泰尔！你他妈的怎么回事！
Tair! What the heck is the matter with you?
我叫你停下！你听到没有！
l told you to stop it! You hear me!
阿波，开枪！她已经不再是泰尔了！
Por, shoot her! She's not Tair anymore!
阿波！不要开枪！
Por! Don't do it!
潘老师，求求你…不要伤害我们，我好害怕
Teacher Panor, please...don't hurt us. l'm afraid!
放了我们吧！
Let us go please!
开枪！开枪啊！
Shoot her! Shoot her!
你真他妈没用！
Damn you!
阿柯！冷静啊，不要开枪！
Ko! Get a grip, don't do it!
你竟敢对我这样大声说话！
You dare raise your voice to me!
阿柯！
Ko!
我让你说！我让你的乌鸦嘴再说话！
Talk! You and your filthy mouth of yours!
现在让你说了！说啊！你怎么不说了？
Now is your chance to talk! Talk! Why don't you talk?
阿柯！你怎么了？
Ko! What the hell is wrong!
Hey Ko! What's the matter with you?
阿柯！你能听到我说话吗？
Ko! Can you hear me?
阿柯！该死的！
Ko! Damn!
阿柯！阿柯！伙计！
Ko! Ko! Hey man!
泰尔！醒醒啊！泰尔！
Tair! Wake up! Tair!
泰尔！快醒醒啊！泰尔！
Tair! Wake up please! Tair!
嘿！阿柯！
Hey! Ko!
阿柯！
Ko!
你们现在打算怎么办？
What are we going to do now?
我们走不了，也就是说…
Since we can't get out of here, that means...
…那个怪人老师就在这附近某处，对我们施以符咒
...that wacked out teacher is somewhere around here, placing spells on us!
阿波，你的意思是我们要…
Por, you mean, you want us to...
没错，轮到我们反击了！
That's right. lt's our turn to mess with her!
我不去！我哪也不去！
l'm not going! l'm not going anywhere!
我们就应该待在这里！
We should stay right here!
小金，你留下来照看她
Kim, you stay and look after her.
阿塔，你和我一起去
Ta, you're coming with me.
等一下！
Wait!
要小心啊！
Be careful!
你们俩都一样
The both of you.
小金，你不要离开我
Kim, don't you leave me here.
他们无处不在！
They are all around us!
我不想看到他们！
l don't want to see them!
泰尔！你看到了什么？
Tair! What do you see?
看到了什么？
Who do you see?
你真的看到了他们吗？他们在哪？
You really see them, don't you? Where are they?
他们在哪？泰尔！他们在哪？
Where are they? Tair! Where are they?
泰尔，你要去哪？
Tair, where are you going?
我们去那里找一下！
Let's check over there!
泰尔！你在哪里？
Tair! Where are you?
泰尔，等我一下！
Tair, wait!
小金！
Kim!
阿塔，等一下！
Ta, wait up man!
阿塔！
Ta!
出来，给我现身！
Come out, show yourself!
小金！
Kim!
小金！你还好吗？
Kim! You okay?
我拉你上来！
l've got you!
现在没事了
You're ok now.
可能会有点疼！
This is gonna hurt!
坐一下吧
Sit for a while.
阿塔，你快去找阿波
Ta, you go check on Por.
我再也走不动了
l can't walk anymore.
你在这里真的没事吗？
You sure you're going to be all right here?
不要靠近我！
Stay away from me!
离我远点！
Keep away from me!
我不想看见你们！
l don't want to see any of you!
泰尔
Tair.
离我远点！
Get away from me!
泰尔，没事的
Tair. lt's ok.
我在这里，你和我在一起没事的
l'm here now. You're with me.
你和我在一起没事的
You'll be fine. l'm right with you.
泰尔，你怎么了啊？
Tair, what's wrong with you?
离我远点！
Stay away from me!
你不要过来！
Don't you come closer!
泰尔，别害怕
Tair. lt's okay.
泰尔！别跑了！
Tair! Stop it!
你不要过来！
Don't you come closer!
泰尔！你要去哪啊，泰尔？
Tair! Where are you going, Tair?
离我远点！
Get away from me!
泰尔
Tair.
走开！我不想看见你们！
Go away! l don't want to see any of you!
离我远点！
Get away from me!
泰尔
Tair.
我不想再看到你们了！
l don't want to see anymore!
这样我就再也看不到你们了！
l won't be able to see you anymore!
泰尔，不要啊！
Tair, stop!
我再也看不到你们了！看不到了！
l won't see you anymore! l can't see!
泰尔！泰尔！
Tair! Tair!
泰尔！
Tair!
小金！
Kim!
泰尔？
Tair?
小金！
Kim!
小金！小金！
Kim! Kim!
先坐下，小金
There you go, Kim.
没事了，小金，没什么好怕的
lt's all right Kim. There's nothing to be afraid of.
我和你在一起
l'm right here with you now.
那么你就不会再离开我了吗？
So now, you don't love me anymore?
阿波，你干什么啊？
Por, what's wrong with you?
现在你怎么了？
What's the matter now?
你刚才是不是拿枪指着我？
Didn't you just point a gun at me?
你觉得你真的能开枪打我吗？
You really think you can shoot me?
阿波！阿波！不要啊！
Por! Por! Don't do it!
开枪啊！
Shoot me!
开枪！
Shoot!
我叫你开枪！
l said shoot me!
扣扳机！
Pull the trigger!
阿波！不要！
Por! No!
阿塔，你他妈的干什么！走开！我要杀了她！
Damn you Ta! Get out of the way! l'm going to kill her!
你疯了吗？
Are you nuts?
离她远点！你疯了吗？
Get away from her! Are you nuts?
快点，小金！
Come on Kim!
你不愿招是吧？
So you don't want to confess, huh?
你这是要到哪去？
Where do you think you are going?
为什么不告诉我真相？
Why don't you tell me the truth?
你是爱我的
You love me.
我会让你招的
l'm going to make you confess.
还是不愿招吗？
Still don't want to confess?
你真的要这样做？
Are you sure about this?
嗯，看来你吸引了不少男人啊
Hmm, you seem to attract a lot of men.
阿塔，我看到你继母和欧教练鬼混
Ta, l saw your stepmom fooling around with that coach O-Larn.
他们正在体育馆里
They're in the gym.
我想让她被狠狠地折磨！
l want her to be brutally tortured!
你一定要帮我！
You have to help me!
我不知道还能找谁帮忙了
l don't know who else to turn to.
听好了，潘老师
Listen well, Mrs. Panor.
你想战胜所遭受到的残酷折磨，只有一个办法
There is only one way that you will be able to win over this ordeal.
你要吃掉那些诅咒你的人的肉
You must eat the flesh of those that cursed you.
但它也可能会同时致你疯狂
But it may make you insane.
因为他的所有力量都会流入你的体内
Because all of his powers will flow in your veins.
现在你能想起些什么了吧？
Can you remember anything now?
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
无论你的过去有多么肮脏，我都会为你洗干净的
No matter how dirty your past is, l'll clean you up good.
我想现在时间到了
l think, it is about time.
求你了！不要伤害我，老师！
Please! Don't hurt me, teacher!
我招了！我全都招了！
l'll confess! l'll confess everything!
就是我鼓动阿塔…
l was the one that encouraged Ta and...
…和他的朋友偷拍你和欧教练的
...his friends to tape you and coach O-Larn together.
就是我对你施加诅咒的
l was the one that put a curse on you.
我不应该那样对你的！
l shouldn't have had that affair with you!
我不应该那样看待你的！
l shouldn't have thought of you that way.
老师求求你放了我吧！
Teacher let me go please!
老师，求求你放了我吧！
Teacher, let me go please!
阿波
Por.
小金？阿塔？
Kim? Ta?
这都是真的吗，阿塔？
Is it true, Ta?
你怎么能这样？
How could you?
小金，求求你救我！小金，我犯了错！
Kim, help me please! Kim, l made a mistake!
我以为我们会永远相爱的，小金！
l thought that we would love each other forever, Kim!
我根本想不到你会这样冷血，我从没想到…
l never thought you could be so cruel. l never thought...
阿塔！阿塔，不要把我丢在这里！
Ta! Ta, don't leave me like this!
你不能和她在一起！不要把我丢在这里！
You can have her! Just don't leave me here!
我们走，阿塔
Let's get out of here, Ta.
阿塔，你个混帐，给我回来！
Ta, you bastard, come back here!
阿塔，你回来！
Ta, come back!
不要丢下我！
Don't leave me.
我不会让你死得那么舒服的，亲爱的
l'm not going to let you get away that easy, my dear.
开枪！
Shoot it!
老师！放开我吧！
Teacher! Let me go!
放开我！
Let me go!
老师，你放开我！
Teacher, you let me go now!
老师，求求你放开我！
Teacher, please let me go!
放开我！
Let me go!
我求你了，放我走吧
l'm begging you to let me go.
老师，我求你放我走吧！
Teacher, please l'm begging you to let me go!
放开我！
Let me go!
求求你，放开我吧！
Please, let me go!
老师，求你不要伤害我！
Teacher, please don't hurt me.
放我走吧！
Just let me go!
老师，我求你放我走吧！
Teacher, l'm begging for you to let me go.
让你看清楚我的脸
You shall see my face clearly.
等下你就要去拜访湿婆了
And then you will pay a visit to the three eyed god.
但我得先给你清洁一下…
However, l have to clean you up first...
不要怕…
Don't worry...
现在你不紧张了吧
There, now you are at ease.
现在该彻底地给你清洁一下了
lt is time to clean you up from the inside out.
阿塔！你继续走吧，我走不动了
Ta! You go on ahead. l can't go on.
不行，小金，我不会丢下你的
No Kim, l won't leave you!
你是不是打算不采取任何行动？
Listen, you're not going to do anything about it?
好吧，我自己搞定
Fine, l'll do something about it!
喂？喂？
Hello? Hello?
喂？小努，宝贝是你吗？
Hello? Noot my dear?
这是谁啊？
Who's this?
我不会让你死得那么舒服的！
l'm not going to let you die that easy!
我要把你送到湿婆那里
l'm going to send you to the three eyed god.
醒来！
Wake up!
现在你够干净了，我准备让你参加这个伟大的仪式了
Now that you are clean enough, l will now prepare you for his greatness.
别动！小姐，你最好放下它！
Freeze! Miss, you better drop it!
开枪！
Fire!
请让开！
Please move away.
让开！
Move away from here!
快让路！
Give us room!
让我们过去！
Please let us pass!
小金，挺住啊
Kim, hang on.
在我们的生命之路上，会有诸多选择…
On the path of life with many choices...
…有时，你根本不知道你的选择会带来怎样的结果
...sometimes we never know what the outcome of our choices will be.
但是，许多次我们知道应该或不应该做一件事情的时候
But then again, many times we know what we should or shouldn't do.
我们却没能做出明智的选择
We just neglect to chose wisely.
但是，这样说却是对的…
However, you may be correct in saying...
…有时，如果我们一开始就做出了正确的选择…
...sometimes if we had made the right choices from the start...
…死神就不会离我们如此之近
...death wouldn't be so close.
我和阿塔都能幸存下来…
Our lives, both mine and Ta's, were spared...
…所以，也许我们都能体会到我们生命的最终意义
...so that we may know what our purpose in life would ultimately be.
既不是为了未来，也不是为了过去
Not for the future, or for the past.
而是现在
But for the present.
我们在任何时刻，都要为自己选择正确的道路
We must choose the correct path at all times for our own sake.
我希望我能时刻看到那些选择
And l hope to see those choices at all times.
我好多了，爸爸
l'm better, Dad.
休息好了吧！我给你带了些吃的
Rest up! Here l brought you some treats.
谢谢妈妈
Thank you mother.
谢谢你来陪我
Thank you for staying with me.
阿塔，我们重新开始，好吗？
Ta, let's start all over again.
好
Yes.
我们现在正在潘老师的犯罪现场
We are now at the crime scene of the teacher, Panor.
警方搜索了潘老师的房子
Police have searched Mrs. Panor's house.
小金…
Kim...
我有些事要告诉你
l have something l have to tell you.
关于我在寄宿学校上学的事，我对你撒了谎
l lied to you about my time at boarding school.
其实我从没有在那里待过
l never stayed there.
我一直没告诉你是因为…
l never told you because...
…我觉得你不会理解我的
...l didn't think you could understand.
在河里找到的最后一具尸体是…
And the last body to be found in the river was...
…阿塔，也就是她的继子的尸体
...Ta, her stepson.
事情过去很久了，我觉得你应该忘了它
lt's been a long time already, l think you should just forget about it.
谢谢
Thank you.
好的，我会帮你收拾好
All right, l'll help you sweep up the place.
回到我身边，好吗？
Come back to me, please?
听着，如果你们要说甜言蜜语，不要在上课时间聊！
Listen, if you guys want to sweet talk each other, do it outside of school time!
打扰他人知道吗
lt's distracting.
我想告诉你，你毕业后我就发现了
l want to tell you what l've discovered after you graduated.
我想让你看到我所看到的一切
l wanted you to see what l've seen.
让其他人体验我所检验过的痛苦
To let others experience the pain, as l've experienced it.
她虐待我们，小金
She treated us badly, Kim.
每个人都死得很恐怖
Everyone died a horrible death.
奶奶是被关在屋里饿死的
Grandma was locked up in the closet, and was starved to death.
而我呢，尽管那不是我的错，我却承担了所有的痛苦
As for me, even though it wasn't my fault, l carried all the pain.
每个人都应该帮我分担痛苦
Everyone should help me bear the pain.
阿波不应该成为你命中的那个人
Por should not be the one for you.
阿波不应该和你在一起，小金
Por wasn't meant for you, Kim.
小金！
Kim!
小金，你还记得吗，你总是想让我靠近你一些
Kim, do you remember, you always wanted me close. Didn't you?
小金，看到那个人了吗？
Hey Kim, you see that guy?
他是校队的明星，我喜欢他
He is star of the school team. l like him.
那你跟我说干嘛？我能把他从你那里抢过来
Why tell me then? I could steal him from you.
别忘了你总是第二名
Don't forget you're always number two in this school.
敢打赌吗？
Want to bet?
如果一周之内他不和我约会的话，我就永远都作第二名
lf in one week, he won't date me, l'll always be second to you.
这种事你一旦尝试…
Things like this, if you try it, and do it...
…它就将终生与你相伴
...it will be with you 'til the day you die!
Fit影视论坛荣誉出品
http://www.fitbbs.com
本字幕仅供学习和交流使用，不得用于任何商业目的
使用本字幕所造成的一切后果皆与 Fit 影视论坛无关